We are known as the Sons of Mithras.
我被Q槊芴乩之子
Ignis fatuus, that's what this Sons of Mithras business is.
鬼火 @就是密特拉神之子的茏
If I marry Camilla Pazzi...
如果我娶了卡米拉・帕吉...
You and I can still snatch a little freedom here and there.
你我仍然可以不r地偷g
Do we kill Lorenzo coming up the path?
要在洛佐^淼穆飞邮?
Strike only when the brothers are together.
只有他兄弟在一起的r候 我才能邮
Lucrezia Donati?
R克蕾RI・多{蒂?
Saddle the horses for Siena. We'll question her directly.
漶R去a耶{ 我面她
- And here's our final savior.  - Gentlemen.
- @位就是最後一位救世主  - 先生
What possesses you to betray Lorenzo, to betray us all?
是什N你背叛洛佐 背叛我大家?
- You are Lucrezia Donati's father.  - Indeed.
- 你是R克蕾RI・多{蒂的父H  - 是的
L'Artista, I see you escaped.
g家 我看到你逃出砹
And I see a key.
而我看到了一把匙
Cosimo de Medici was a Son of Mithras.
科西莫・美第奇是密特拉之子
A ship provisioned for a journey.
一艘b了探Uao的船
The Vault of Heaven is out there.
天穹就在那
Allahu Akbar.
真主至上
What does the future hold for the Sons of Mithras, Al-Rahim?
阿拉希姆 密特拉之子的命\如何?
Augury is a tricky business.
占卜是y以捉摸的
I see grim tidings.
我看到了怒的潮水
Darkness, despair.
oM的黑暗和^望
The usual cant and caper, then.
一如既往的言Z啊
You would make light of our circumstances, Cosimo de Medici?
你情r好起淼  科西莫・美第奇?
Light is the only thing that sustains me, my friend.
然了 我的朋友 唯一支挝业木褪枪饷
Are there no bright spots on the horizon, then?
地平上有福音出F?
There is one, a boy from Vinci.
有一姆移淼哪泻
He has promise.
他大有希望
Even now, events conspire to bring him to Florence.
即便使p 也要把他У椒鹆__
Am I to keep an eye on him?
需要我盯他?
Only from a distance.
e靠太近
He must ascend or fall by his own devices.
他必靠自己的造成功或者失
And speaking of devices,
f到造
we give you this for safe-keeping.
我你保o它的安全
Someone will come for this when it is time to make the journey.
r候到了 自然有人碚宜
Perhaps, the boy Al-Rahim speaks of.
或S就是那阿拉希姆提到的男孩
Assuming he survives his trial.
如果他能捱^磨y的
I have faith he will.
我相信 他的
If I'm to keep the candles burning,
如果要我保o火N的
I'll need more reassurances than faith and a vague prophecy.
要S我以保C 而不能HH有h渺的信念和模糊的A言
I'm afraid I cannot give you any reassurances.
恐怕我不能o你任何保C
If the future indicated by these signs comes to pass,
如果卜卦@示的命\成真
only one of us will live to see it.
我中就只有一人能活到那r候
So which lucky one gets to survive?
那N是l能存?
You misunderstand.
你e了
The dead will be the lucky ones.
死去的才是幸\的人
The one who lives to see this future...
活下砜吹轿淼娜...
he will truly suffer.
涫苷勰
I'm going to miss this place.
我想念@地方的
And you. I'll miss you as well, my friends.
有你 我十分炷畹 我的朋友
We've followed you into more scrapes than I care to count.
我意^m跟S你
Why not add another to the tally?
槭颤N不е我?
I can't ask you to follow me across an ocean.
我不能求你跟S我漂洋^海
We want to, Maestro.
我意 大
The Vault of Heaven, the Book of Leaves,
天穹 ~之 你找到他的r候
we want to be there when you find them.
我想陪在你身
The boy's a half-wit moon-calf
@孩子虼赖
who'd smother his balls in ox dung if you told him to.
就算你他把小弟弟插在牛SY 他也照k的
As for me? I've accrued some gambling debts
至於我? 我nn
that make my near-term residence in Florence problematic.
都付不起在佛__的快到期的房租了
So where to next? We'll need a ship, won't we?
下一站是哪耗? 我需要一艘船 Π?
The Portuguese are establishing
葡萄牙人和西非的Q易往
trade routes along Western Africa.
日益l繁
We'll book passage to the Canary Islands.
我要乘船去卡{Yu
After that, we'll have to improvise.
之後 就走一步算一步
First, I've certain accounts to settle with the House of Medici.
不^首先 我要去和美第奇家族算一P
Why bother with the Medicis? Why not skirt Florence entirely?
槭颤N扯上美第奇家族? 槭颤N不氐下佛__的事情?
There are things I have to say to Lorenzo.
有些事 我必要和洛佐f
Words for his ears alone.
只能H口跟他f
Shall we meet at the Barking Dog this evening?
那我今晚在吠犬酒店碰^?
Why not? A pint, one last foray into a Florentine slit for luck.
槭颤N不呢? 喝一品酒 最後一次突u佛__人 碰碰\
We can see if Nico's balls have dropped.
我能看看尼科量如何
That's odd.
奇怪
That's a Lanner Falcon.
地中海隼
They're rare this side of the Adriatic.
他很少出F在德Y海
Turkey, Africa, yes. But here?
在土耳其和非洲有可能到 但是@?
- It lost its way. It happens.  - No, not often.
- f不定它迷路了 有可能  - 不
The last time I saw a Lanner
最後一次我看@NB是
was the day my mother disappeared.
在我母Hx_那天
- You say they hail from Turkey?  - Mm.
- 你f它碜酝炼其?  - 嗯
I'll wager that bird's an omen, meant for you alone.
我打@bBδ碚f是赫
I should follow it.
我跟著它
I said it's an omen. If anything, you should ride in the opposite direction.
我f了 @是赫 如果真有什N事情 你也往反方向跑啊
- I'll meet you at the Dog.  - Leo!
- 我酒店  - R昂!
Yah!
{!
I take it you now believe in visions...
我敢f F在你相信...
and demons?
和耗Я?
Where can be Giuliano be?
朱利Z去哪毫?
How badly did you handle your talk with him about this marriage?
姻的事 你和他得有多糟糕?
He knew he had to wed the girl.
他知道他必娶@女孩
He agreed there was no other way
他也J]有e的k法
to halt our feud with the Pazzis,
砥较⒑团良家的世仇了
yet I've not seen a trace of him for days.
但我好多天都]看他了
Did you actually hear him utter the words, "I agree",
你是到他f"意"字
or did you only hear what you wanted to hear?
是只了你想到的部分?
He agreed.
他就是同意了
Giuliano may not arrive at all.
朱利Z可能根本不砹
I say we strike.
我行影
Kill Lorenzo and Clarice while we have them here.
趁洛佐和克拉z都在 ⒘怂
Are you so blind to the success of your rivals?
你想用你的愚蠢沓扇κ值某晒?
The brothers are popular.
民意向著他兄弟二人
Murdering only one will allow the survivor
⒁ 只存者
to rally the city against us.
更有能力FY民Ω段
Only with the shock of losing both men at once
只有在同r失去兄弟的重下
will Florence bow to new leaders.
佛__才接受新的Iд
You can send your men after Giuliano, wherever he is.
不管朱利Z在哪Y 你都可以派人⒘怂
I can handle Lorenzo myself.
我能自己解Q洛佐
Do so and you defy the will of Rome, Francesco.
如果@N做 弗朗切斯科 你就忤逆了_R的意志
I warn you now.
我F在警告你
Remarkable.
太神奇了
According to lore,
f
these will open the Vault of Heaven.
@把匙能打_天穹
Solomon Ogbai, the Abyssinian, told you its location?
那阿比西尼人 所_T・W拜告V你具w方位了?
He told me it rested
他跟我f
on an old peak, in a town made of stone.
在古老山}上的一座石^小Y
Beneath something called "the hitching post of the sun."
天穹就在太之柱下面
With these keys and the map to the Vault itself,
有了@把匙和去天穹的地D
it would appear the Book of Leaves lies firmly within our grasp.
~之就牢牢掌握在我手中了
When was the last time the Book was actually seen?
~之最後一次出F是什Nr候?
A thousand years ago.
千年之前
When the Library of Alexandria burned.
v山大D^被S之H
Yet we still have faith it exists.
但我相信它存在著
Faith.
相信
It always comes down to that, doesn't it?
是@ 不是?
Never anything that can be proven. Just...
]有什N事情得到C明 只是...
It's just smoke.
只是漫的F
It's tales by the camp fire.
只是篝火旁的童
You're angry.
你生饬
Pope Sixtus claims you're an agent of the Ottomans.
西斯V教皇f你是土耳其的人
The Sons of Mithras are not constrained
密特拉之子是不
by geographic borders.
受地理界限所限的
Our stewardship encompasses all mankind.
我的使命P乎整人
Well, this particular man
那N 我@立的w
is tired of being manipulated.
倦了被操v
If you are lost in a forest and you see a landmark,
如果你在森林Y迷路的r候看了一路
is that landmark manipulating you along a certain path?
那N你能f@路嗽诓倏v著你通往出口?
I am merely your guide.
我只是你的引д
But if I ignore your chosen path, then...
但如果我不走你x的路...
I'll never find my mother, will I?
我就永h找不到母H了 Π?
She's a poor little thing.
她可真可z
Mending Camilla Pazzi's heart will be the least of our concerns
如果我弟弟牧诉@鲅 那卡米拉・帕吉不心
if my brother sabotages this feast.
就oPo要了
The snub could propel us all into still more years of blood feud.
我的怠慢或S使血鹩演愈烈
Look at Francesco. Look at them all.
看看弗朗切斯科 看看他
- The Pazzis glower like that. - Exactly.
- 帕吉家在号火  - ]e
Today was supposed to be different.
今天本是斫Q矛盾的
How long should we wait?
我要等多久?
Always so impatient, Francesco.
e是那N]耐性 弗朗切斯科
Talk with them.
去和他ff
Complain of the scandal of Giuliano's absence.
抱怨朱利Z的缺席
Your anger at the cur's impudence
你δ狗sN的怒
will disguise your desire to kill.
能很好的掩你的C
Or it may just spur me to strike even faster.
或者只能刺激我提前邮
Captain, tracking the comings and goings of Florentines is your specialty.
L 你的特L是知道佛__人的行
Where is my brother?
我的弟弟在哪?
I cannot say.
我不知道
A week ago, my Officer Bertino asked permission
一周之前 我的手下博蒂Z命
to accompany Giuliano to Siena.
陪同朱利Z去a耶{
I've seen neither of them since.
哪阂葬 我再]^他
Why Siena?
槭颤N去a耶{?
Giuliano,
朱利Z
apparently longed for one last fling before his nuptials.
@然是想在Y婚之前再狂一把
The pious Bertino promised to keep him from too much trouble.
博蒂Z很忠\ 他l誓保o他的
What if Bertino failed?
但如果博蒂Z出事了呢?
What if Giuliano was waylaid on the road?
如果朱利Z遭到埋伏了呢?
Surely that's the only reason he'd insult us
然 @是他用缺席硇呷栉的
with his absence today.
唯一解
Take a few men and search the roads
上你的人 在佛__和a耶{之g
between Florence and Siena.
沿路搜
All of us yearn to know what has become of Giuliano, Captain.
L 我都非常迫切想知道朱利Z的下落
Settle the matter for us. Please.
M快槲找到他 xx
There is a ship bound for Cape Verde, the Basilisk.
有一艘停在佛得角的船 皇冠蜥蜴
Under the command of Antonio de Noli.
那是安|尼W・ZY的船
As we speak, de Noli is in Florence,
我v的r候 ZY正在佛__
loading a barge with provisions for a journey.
往船上\送配o 樗的旅途做
At dawn, he takes the barge to Pisa,
黎明r 他⒊倘ネ比_
where the Basilisk is anchored.
就是皇冠蜥蜴下^的地方
You, Leonardo, must book passage on that ship.
R昂{多 你必乘那艘船去
With your navigational skills,
{你的航海技g
the Basilisk will survive the storms
皇冠蜥蜴才能扛^暴L雨
and reach another land entirely,
抵_另一片地
where the Book of Leaves awaits.
也就是~之所在的地方
Some years ago, a magician promised me he would hide something for you.
多年以前 一魔g士答我槟悴匾患|西
A magician?
魔g士?
Cosimo de Medici?
科西莫・美第奇?
Cached within Cosimo's tomb is a mariner's astrolabe.
科西莫墓Y有一航海星P
With it, you will navigate the Basilisk safely
利用它你能判e方向 {皇冠蜥蜴
to the lands indicated on the map.
到_地D上擞的地方
Cosimo hid it in a way that only you would solve his riddle.
科西莫把它藏了起 只有你能解_i 找到它
As ever, you know the right games to tantalize me.
又要像以前一 用你的[硗媾我
You must carry the astrolabe onto that barge.
你必е星P上g船
The Book of Leaves, of your mother's fate,
P乎你母H命\的~之
will remain a mystery.
仍是一i
Isn't this the moment where you spin a coin,
@不是你旋D硬
put me into a trance?
砻曰笪业r候了?
No coins.
]有硬
No trances.
]有迷惑
You either book passage West or you don't.
要Nx西部走廊 要N不x
You succeed or you fail.
要N成功 要N失
The choice and the consequences are yours.
Q定由你碜 後果由你沓
- Be still, child.  - I'm going to be sick.
- eo 孩子  - 我快病了
You're already sick. No-one calls for me if they're well.
你已病了 ]病l也不找我
Here. Hold this.
o Ao
You've not stepped over a grave, have you?
你]上跨^吧?
Or drunk milk that's gone to spoil?
]喝本硪倒掉的牛奶吧?
No, Ottavia. Nothing like that.
] W塔S ]诌^那拥氖
Here. Piss into this.
o 尿M去
I saw a butcher's daughter last week, blubbering on about a malady akin to this.
上周我到一屠夫的女 因似的病Y而哭[
Had to split her open. Worms.
不得不把她剖_ Y全是x子
Oh. Cloudy as a winter's dawn.
天啊 @N
Is that bad?
很乐?
A pinch or two of this every two days,
每商斐砸恍〈檫@
and be sure to stay out of the light of the moon.
有 e月光了
- Not for your sack, but for his.  - For whom?
- 不是榱四 是榱怂  - 檎l?
Your son, you know where the worms go, you're with child.
你鹤 你也知道x子跑哪去了 你言辛
Bring me to him.
我去他
I've sent Clarice away to spare her whatever tragedy you may have brought here.
不管你砹耸颤N噩耗 克拉z都不看到
Delay no more. Show me.
e再拖延了 o我看看
My Officer Bertino. Found on the road to Siena.
我的傧虏┑僦Z 被lF死在去a耶{的路上
Hacked to death. Bandits?
被砍死的 是I干的?
Most likely. Yet we found no trace of Giuliano.
很有可能 不^]找到朱利Z的E
Take more men. Find him, alive or dead.
多些人去 找到他 活要人 死要
I must know my brother's fate.
我一定要知道弟弟的命\
Where am I?
我@是在哪?
In the Val d'Elsa, Signor.
先生 你在埃_谷口
We found you in the river, more dead than alive.
我暮友Y救出你r 你一b半_都踏M鬼TP了
I nursed your wounds.
我o你包了口
I thank you for that.
xx你
Soon as I seen your clothes, I knew you was a nobleman.
一看衣服就知道 你是F人
And yet, you didn't rob me.
可你s]劫我
Wouldn't be Christian.
劫不是基督徒的作L
What day is it? How long have I been out?
今天周? 我昏迷了多久?
Holy Saturday, Signor.
先生 今天是}L六
When they laid Christ's body in the tomb.
是基督企w入的日子
Argh!
啊呀!
I have to get back to Florence.
我得回佛__去
I need to warn Lorenzo.
我要去提醒洛佐
You need to rest, son.
你需要休息 小伙子
I can't.
我不能休息
No time.
]rg了
Hm. The dead still walk.
呵 死人能走路
I assumed you had to be dead.
我以槟阍缢懒
Some said you traveled to Wallachia, others to Rome.
有人f你去了瓦拉吉 有人f你去了_R
- Which was it?  - Both.
- 你去了哪Y?  - 都去了
Ah. Both.
啊 都去了
So why are we meeting here? Hm?
那楹我在此相?
What intrigue are you involving me in this time?
你@次又想我赃M什N\?
This tomb, you designed it for Cosimo?
@是你榭莆髂O的墓吧?
To an extent.
可以@Nf
Like Cosimo's portrait,
@座墓不
is it possible this tomb contains secret mysteries?
像科西莫的一 [含著什N秘密呢?
This mosaic, see how the circles
瞧瞧@些R克 @些圈圈
weave through the design.
在整O中的制邮
Step back and focus only on that.
後退 只看@|西
King Solomon's Knot.
所_T王的Y
The ancient symbol representing the wisdom of eternity.
代表著永a智慧的古老符
Yes.
]e
Other men live among the trappis of this world.
生均榉彩滤_
But Cosimo's face was always turned beyond
科西莫的思想
worldly distractions
不被世俗所
to the universe above.
而只P注世俗之上的宇宙
He had the most agile mind I've ever known...
他思S敏捷 世所罕...
until I met you.
你c他不相上下
You honor me.
^了
You're the closest thing I've ever known to a father.
ξ碚f 你是最接近父H@Q^的人了
I'm about to leave you again.
我即⒃俅坞x_你
This time, on a quest from which I may never return.
@一次是可能回不淼淖ぶ旅
Every question you answer leads to another question.
你所回答的每一} 都砍隽硗獾}
And such quests lead many to nothing but misery.
@拥淖 得到的只有痛苦
The true misery
真正的痛苦
is if all the questions are solved,
是所有的}都被解Q了
cos then there's nothing left to ask.
那r候就再也]什N可的了
- Where do you voyage now?  - It depends on what I find here.
- 你如今想到哪Y去?  - @要看我在@旱陌lF
I designed no secret compartment.
我不不o而e
Ah! But...
啊! 但是...
but the Magician
但是魔g
could install one without anyone knowing.
可以神不知鬼不X地施
Like a flaw.
就像瑕疵一
Cosimo would never have permitted it.
科西莫不@N做的
And yet...
而且...
Look. Look! Do you see?
瞧 快看! 看到]?
It's exactly the same as the semi-circles
@和所_T王的YY的半A
in King Solomon's Knot.
完全一模一
And Cosimo's gaze reflected
而科斯莫的P注c
on Libra,
也反映在天秤座上
the scales of balance.
即平衡的天秤上
Perhaps there's a matching discrepancy?
或S有相的偏差?
Here. Do you see? There. Look.
@ 看到]? 那 看吧
Do they form an axis?
它是不是成了一lS?
Well, if so, then there must be another axis that crosses it.
@拥脑 必定有另外一lSc之相交
Exactly.
]e
Starting here.
倪@Y_始
Then its mate would be...
那它的交c在...
Here. Look.
@ 快看
The center of the knot
Y的中心
would be...
...
directly above the heart.
在心K的正上方
The question answered.
@}解Q了
Which leads to another question.
也就又有了}
Yes.
]e
Magnificently so.
_如此
Signor!
先生!
Signor Medici, where have you been?
美第奇w下 你去了哪Y?
What's befallen you?
你出什N事了?
Treachery. A moment alone, Captain?
背叛 L 能借一步f?
Bertino and I determined Lucrezia Donati to be a spy.
博蒂Z和我_J了R克蕾RI・多{蒂是g
You cannot mean it.
你不是J真的吧
We sought her out in Siena, and came across her being attacked by bandits.
我在a耶{找到了她 正好碰一Iu羲
We dispatched them but at the cost of Bertino's life.
我敉肆I 但是博蒂Zs奚了
Lucrezia stabbed me.
R克蕾RI捅了我
Left me for dead.
以槲宜懒
She is an agent of Riario and Pope Sixtus.
她是瑞阿里W和西斯V教皇的g
Capaldi! Ride with Black Martin. Tell Lorenzo Giuliano lives.
卡波蒂! TR跟布R克・R丁先走 告V洛佐 朱利Z活著
I will escort him home at a pace his wounds allow. Go. Go!
我根他的莞上你的 走 快走!
Thank you, Captain, for your consideration.
xx你 L 考]得真周到
It is nothing.
@不算什N
Someone needs to tend to you.
得有人黻P照你
We had a contract.
我有^合s
You break it and I will be justified
你`反它 我就有
in depriving you of your freedom.
Z你的自由
And what happened to the last man
那上次那把我
who tried to pen me up in Florence?
PM佛__Oz的人怎N恿?
You'll find me more of a match to you
你lF比起那倒霉的法官
than that hapless magistrate.
我更配做你的κ
I would.
的_
What about a small duchy of your own?
你一片封地如何?
That would give you the freedom to amass
@幽憔涂梢宰杂傻W
all the knowledge you like.
你想W的知R了
And you have duchies sitting around
你手的I地多到
to hand out like party favors?
可以S便分l了?
The Duke of Urbino and I made an alliance to move on the Papacy.
比Z公爵和我已同盟抗教皇
That will give us the ability to give you
我很快就有能力
the legitimacy you have never had.
o你]有^的pn
I suspect your alliance is dead.
我恐怕你的同盟已胎死腹中
At the Vatican I saw the Duke of Urbino himself.
我在梵蒂H眼看到了比Z公爵
One can't miss the man. He looked quite at home.
他可不是容易忽的人 他在那相自在
So as you desert me, you bring me word that
你x我而去以後 砀嬖V我 我唯一
my only other source of military defense
能依的事防R力量
is a sham?
已不能指望了?
You approached him because you knew he had a price, yes?
你找上他也是以樗能虮皇召I 不是?
Someone outbid you.
有人出r比你高
Fuck you.
胡f
Artists approach me all the time.
有g家找上我
They are full of vague and glorious ideas
MX子模糊又堂皇的想法
on which they rarely deliver.
可他]F^
Case in point.
@就是例子
You were warned.
有人警告^你
You were warned in this very room.
有人在@g屋子Y就警告^你
I accept many commissions, I finish few.
我收了很多酬金s完成了很少的任
I gave you the chance to be the foremost artist of your day.
我o了你成樽铒L光的g家的C
I gave you the most desirable woman in Florence as a subject.
我把佛__最有魅力的女人o你做模特
She was never my subject.
她矶疾皇俏业哪Ｌ
You and I love this city, do we not?
你我都圻@座城市 不是?
We do.
]e
Then help me save it.
那就臀艺救她
What else can I give you?
我能o你什N?
What about her?
她怎N?
Her husband's clearly not an obstacle.
她的丈夫@然不是}
You think I would just toss her to you just like that?
你J槲@Np易地就把她o你?
You have a wife.
你已有妻子了
Who has her charms. Who needs attention.
同用利 同有枰你的P心
How much does Lucrezia mean to you, Lorenzo?
R克蕾RIδ碚f有多重要 洛佐?
Are you willing to set aside your toy
你意榱税盐伊粼诜鹆__
to keep me in Florence?
而放你的玩偶?
Magnifico, your brother has been found.
大人 您的弟弟已被找到了
Giuliano is alive.
朱利Z活著
Wounded but alive.
受了 但活著
Who wounded him?
l弄了他?
Lucrezia Donati.
R克蕾RI・多{蒂
- And she is also alive? - It appears so.
- 那她也活著?  - 似乎是的
What was she doing attacking Giuliano?
她槭颤N要攻糁炖Z?
Did she know of your plans?
她知道你的了?
Giuliano is unarmed and  in the care of Dragonetti.
朱利Z手o寸F 德拉戈{迪在照他
He won't live to see Florence again.
他不活著回到佛__了
But if people learn Giuliano has been killed,
但如果有人知道朱利Z被⒘
Lorenzo will rally the people behind him.
洛佐得到人民的支持
We must strike at Lorenzo first.
我必先拿下洛佐
Easter Mass.
突罟撒
Dawn tomorrow we will poison Lorenzo in the very act
明天黎明我在洛佐的}餐Y邮帜_
of taking holy communion,
毒死他
and damn Cardinal Orsini's pious hesitations.
W西尼唯唯ZZ的虔\鬼去
It will look as if God himself has taken down the tyrant.
就像上帝H自下手Z走裁者的性命
- What is your name?  - Capaldi.
- 你叫什N名字?  - 卡波蒂
Find Father Bagnone and Father Maffei.
去找巴尼W壬窀负婉R菲神父
Have them prepare the Host for Lorenzo,
他浜媒o洛佐的}
and his wife,
有他妻子的
and all his daughters.
以及他所有女旱
Then ride back to Dragonetti and make sure that Giuliano has met his death.
然後TR去找德拉戈{迪 _保朱利Z必死o疑
Consider it done, my lord.
必不辱命 大人
Within hours... we will own Florence.
仔r之後... 佛__就是我的了
But why would Lucrezia agree to act as Rome's catspaw?
但是槭颤NR克蕾RI_R利用?
Sixtus only rewards his own blood.
西斯V任人唯H
Did you know he's already rewarded six of his nephews as cardinals?
你知道他已把他的六侄子任命榧t衣大主教了?
- He is loyal.  - To the point of incestuousness.
- 他很衷心  - 到了y的地步
The virtue of a republic like Florence
佛__的美德在於
is that offices go to the most worthy,
能者才能居之
appointments are made only on merit.
能者才能上任
I dare say you earned your rank on the basis of achievement, Dragonetti?
我敢f你的位是你通^努力取得的 德拉戈{迪 Π?
I did.
的_
And you demonstrate that repeatedly.
而你不止一次地C明了自己
The details in your curfew ledgers
多了你`反宵禁的名
without them, Bertino and I could never have uncovered
]有它 博蒂Z和我永h不lF
the name of Lorenzo's betrayer.
背叛洛佐的人
All one needed was the time to study the records.
其只需要花rg研究
And you had the time, of course.
然 你就有@rg
I do take my work seriously.
我_很J真地Υ我的工作
That's how she was able to avoid detection after curfew, isn't it?
所以她在宵禁後躲^了z查 Π?
She had the perfect alibi, fucking my brother,
她不在隼碛珊艹浞 忙著和我哥哥偷情
and because the first man to raise questions about her activities
而第一岩伤酉虻娜
was already in league with Rome himself.
早就站到_R那了
I could try and ride away.
我逃跑也]用
But you're unwounded, your mount is fresher.
你毫未 R也更加健
Finish what your spy began, then.
那就⒘宋野
Perhaps she'll reward you between her legs.
或S她跟你上床
- That is not what spurs me.  - What does?
- 我想要的不是@  - 那是什N?
A desire for a Florence that fears God,
渴望一敬畏上帝的佛__
not its masters.
而不是害怕主人的
Let's get to your brother's side.
我去找你哥哥
De Noli's barge, bound for Pisa?
ZY的船 _往比_的?
Aye, Signor.
是的 先生
How much to book passage for three?
三位置多少X?
We take only freight and baggage.
我只\物和行李
I told you, only freight and baggage.
告V你了 只\物和行李
I have to board the Basilisk.
我必登上王冠蜥蜴
Yeah, you're beginning to look like baggage.
恩 @下看起硐裥欣盍
Dawn tomorrow. Don't be late.
明早黎明 et到
Each of my brigades awaits near one of these gates.
每都在其中一T附近
You may consider Florence already under our control.
可以f佛__已在我的掌控之下了
- Your men are loyal to you?  - But of course.
- 你的人忠\?  - 然
Because if they get battle-hungry and invade prematurely,
如果他Z不足提前入侵的
the Florentines will rise against them.
佛__人^起反抗的
The Florentines are shopkeepers and clerks.
佛__人只是店主和店T
We're soldiers.
我是士兵
The Florentines live in narrow corridors and alleyways
佛__人住在M窄的走廊和小巷中
where they can strike unexpectedly.
他可以出其不意地攻
If they rise to fight for their home,
如果他楸Ｐl家@而^起
it will not resemble the fields of battle you know.
有一瞿奈匆^的痿Y
We have new weapons for street warfare.
我有新武器打街^
You will follow our lead.
你要我指]
The Pazzis' role in all this is to overthrow the tyrants,
帕吉家族在此g的角色是推翻暴君
establish a clear new regime.
建立一全新的王
While your role is only to appear if summoned
而你的角色只是被镜r候出F一下
to cement the powers-that-will-be into place.
固即⒊闪⒌恼嗟牡匚
If I choose to move on Florence myself...
如果我x为M入佛__...
who are you to stop me?
你又{什N阻r我?
Tell me, who is it that pays your men?
告V我 是lB你的伍的?
You sit in the middle, conveying their wages
你高高在上 o他lY
which issue from the vaults of Rome.
用的可是_R的X
Act against me,
`背我
and that same city shall brand you a heretic,
_Ro你打上教徒的烙印
strip you of your titles, and excommunicate you.
你的^ 把你逐出教
Resist further, and His Holiness
^m反抗 大主教
will have that metal eyepiece of yours melted down
把你的金傺壅秩刍
and poured over your testicles in the middle of the Piazza Navona.
在{沃{V驳侥愕牟G丸上
I've seen what he's capable of with... both of my eyes.
我R^他的能力... 是p眼所
Your man returns.
你的人回砹
Perhaps with news from my brother.
或S有我哥哥的消息
He comes not from Il Magnifico...
他不是拇笕四淼...
but from Count Riario...
而是娜鸢⒗W伯爵那...
to confirm I've killed you.
_J我已⒘四
Why is he not riding away with news I'm still alive?
那他致锊е我活著的消息x_?
I think he has another plan.
我想他另有打算
Hold.
停下
- What are you doing?  - What's best for Florence.
- 你要做什N?  - 做Ψ鹆__最好的事
Aargh!
啊!
Pick up his sword.
炱鹚的
You'll need a weapon if you're going to save your brother.
要救你哥哥 你需要武器
Do it now, Giuliano. Before I change my mind again.
快 朱利Z 趁我]改主意
It's me.
是我
You think I don't know your footsteps?
你以槲衣不出你的_步?
Give me a reason...
o我理由...
why I shouldn't puncture your neck this instant.
我槭颤N不F在就刺穿你的脖子
Not today.
今天不行
You poisoned Vanessa and I risked dementia trying to save her.
你o瓦妮莎下毒 我榫人差cV呆
You shared the secrets of my war machinery with Riario
你告V了瑞阿里WC器的秘密
and put the city at peril.
@座城市陷入危C
This... this denunciation
@... @封揭l信
that names me a sexual criminal,
指控我性侵
had me thrown in jail to face the bonfire.
把我投MOz 等待火刑
This is your work!
都是你值暮檬!
I had Nico send you to the convent to keep your friend alive.
是我尼科把你У叫薜涝壕饶闩笥训拿
I begged for your mercy during the trial
判r我槟闱笄
and made enemies who seek my life.
湎铝讼肴∥倚悦的橙
You will never understand the risks I have taken...
你不知道我冒了多大的U...
- To keep your father alive.  - What?
- 你父H活命  - 什N?
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
He wishes me to tell you how much he loves you.
他希望我告V你他有多勰
I spoke with him in his cell in Castel Sant'angelo.
我在}天使堡的OzY和他^了
Then you grasp the hold they have maintained over me.
然後你利用了他ξ业目刂
It's a hold so strong...
@N控制太大了...
that you would even poison an innocent man.
你σo辜的人下毒
And what of the risks you have faced in search of your mother?
你檎夷隳赣H又冒了多大的U呢?
Huh?
哈?
If it fell to you to keep her alive,
如果是你能Q定她的生死
would you say "No, I'll preserve another's life"?
你f"不 我可救另一人的命"?
I would find another way.
我找到e的k法
Yeah, how easy it is for you to believe that.
是啊 你f起砜烧媸禽p
I would understand your actions, Lucrezia...
我理解你的行 R克蕾RI...
if your father hadn't rejected my offer to set him free.
若不是你父H拒^了他自由的C
- You're lying.  - No.
- 你在撒e  - ]有
You've committed these sins for nothing.
你犯的@些罪都是徒
Your work argues that man is capable of anything.
你的作品都想C明人是否o所不能
Well, between us, we prove it.
你我就是C明
You show us the heights that we can reach and I show us the depths.
你展F了人ゴ蟮O限 而我是h旱O限
Of late...
最近...
I've met men who dwell in shadows,
我遇了身居黑暗中的智者
speaking of... other times and other lives.
他ξ姨崞... 另一世界
Maybe... if they're correct...
或S... 如果他所f是真的...
a life exists in which we...
有另一世界存在於我...
Yes. Yes.
是 是的
Yes.
是
No, I can't do this. I can't.
不行 我不能@ 我不能
- Please. Please.  - I can't. I can't.
- 求求你 求求你  - 我不能 不能
I have to go. I have to...
我必走了 我必...
A ship waits in Pisa to take me to the Book of Leaves.
停在比_的一l船⑤d我ふ胰~之
If I'm not on the Basilisk...
要是我]有登上王冠蜥蜴...
Riario and the Pazzis are moving on Florence.
瑞阿里W和帕吉的已逼近佛__
- They want to kill Lorenzo.  - I could care less, what they do.
- 他想⒙佐  - 我不必在乎他
Let the politicians kill each other, that's their forte.
政客互相吧 那是他的ｉL
Leonardo, please, you are only one who can stop this now.
R昂{多 求求你 如今只有你能阻止@一切
If you're not going to do it for me or for Lorenzo,
要是你不槲液吐佐
then do it for Florence.
榉鹆__阻止他
For Florence?
榉鹆__?
For Florence? The city that turned its back on me?
榉鹆__? @座背叛我的城市?
The bastard son?
我@私生子?
The sodomite?
我@uΨ?
A younger Da Vinci might've bought your arguments, Lucrezia.
那暗倪_芬奇可能你 R克蕾RI
But... I've endured too much these last few months
但是... 月砦胰淌艿奶多了
to be swayed by sentiment.
我不再被情w左右
It's Easter.
F在是突罟
If Florence demands a sacrifice...
如果佛__需要祭品...
I suggest you offer yourself.
我建h你I上自己
You still endeavor to taint the air with that foul stench, I see.
你在用那臭味污染空饽
A vice.
我的毫
One that Girolamo sees fit to allow me.
但吉_拉摩允S我抽
Not the only one.
你不只有一毫
I've never understood your obsession with this game.
我不明白你楹@[蛉绱酥迷
I imagine you've played thousands of times,
我想像你玩了浊П
and what has it brought you?
它能你o什N?
Know thy self,
湍阒己
know thine enemy.
湍阒彼
It is but a recreation.
@不^是休f[
True strategic mastery
真正的\略
must be forged in the arena of life.
只能在生活的技錾襄造
- Happy Easter.  - Indeed.
- 突罟快  - 的_快
For today brings not only the resurrection of Christ...
因榻裉觳恢够督突...
but the resurrection of Florence under Rome's rule.
佛__也⒃诹_R的y治下团d
Soon, all the Italian states will fall into line.
很快 意大利Ty一
I will then turn my attention
然後我把D移注意力D移到
to the true enemy of God...
上帝的真正橙松...
the Ottoman Empire.
W斯曼帝
A final Holy War.
最後l右雎}
A glorious victory for which I will be made...
x煌的倮⑹刮冶蛔u...
a saint.
一位}者
Beware of practicing your righteousness
你一定要得在人民面前
before other people in order to be seen by them,
表F自己的正直
for then there will be no reward from your Father...
因槿嗣癫哪愕纳系勰茄Y...
who is in heaven.
得到任何好
I must thank you.
我必感x你
For without you, I could never have achieved today's triumph.
因]有你 我不有今天的成就
And for this, perhaps you would offer me...
@诱f 或S你o我...
something in return?
一c回?
Hmm.
嗯
I believe it's time you and I...
F在是r候 你和我...
played another game.
再下一局了
Don't you agree... Brother?
同意吧... 兄弟?
Is all in place?
都浜昧?
Fathers Bagnone and Maffei are preparing the poison.
巴尼W群婉R菲神父正在涠舅
And the Cardinal?
那大主教呢?
He's too fucking pious to be told of this change of plans.
他太他虔\了 我]敢告V他有
While he prays, the priests will deliver the tainted Eucharist to Lorenzo.
祈\r 神父把}餐捧o洛佐
Quattrone. Medici loyalist.
@人是F特_ 美蒂奇的忠\支持者
If he goes against us,
要是和我作起
he'll join Lorenzo in the afterlife.
他成鬼也支持洛佐
Is there any news of Da Vinci?
有_芬奇的消息?
The last I heard, he was in Rome.
上次我收到消息r 他在_R
He's countered us again and again!
他每次和咱作!
Can we act if we don't know the man's whereabouts?
我不知他的下落 可以行?
Calm yourself, Francesco.
定c 弗朗切斯科
We have long prepared. All is ready.
我渲苋 一切待命
Signorina, you make an old man...
女士 你我@老^...
believe in the perfectibility of mankind.
也相信人看起砜梢匀绱送昝
Thank you, Maestro.
xx你 大
What troubles you, Vanessa?
你怎N了 瓦妮莎?
Have you seen Giuliano de Medici?
你看朱利Z・美第奇了?
I must speak to him. He needs to hear this.
我要他 我有和他f
Quickly, before the Cardinal sees.
快c e大主教看
Ensure that these wafers go to the Medicis,
_保@些}送到美蒂奇家族那
and only the Medicis.
e出差e
And then we can truly celebrate this mass.
然後我就能真正c祝撒了
Happy Easter, Lorenzo.
突罟快 洛佐
And to you, Francesco.
你也是 弗朗切斯科
Where is Giuliano?
朱利Z在哪?
I'm sure Dragonetti will bring him straight here.
我相信德拉戈{迪他淼
I'm sure of nothing today.
我今天心Y]底
God's trousers, Leo. Where the fuck have you been all night?
上帝啊 R昂 你昨夜到底去哪了?
Only haunted by a final farewell.
道ermp了一下
The barge is loaded and the captain's keen to depart.
船b好後 船L急著x岸
Impatient canker blossom threatened to double the fee if he waited any longer.
那威{f再等的 就把票r翻倍
Well... then let's save some coin
好吧... 那咱省cX
and be on our way.
s快上船吧
What's this?
@是什N?
This is us asking the Fates where the fuck you've been.
我用@占卜你到底是去哪Y了
The Chariot. Reversed?
疖 逆位的?
Uncontrolled passion, leading to defeat.
不受控制的激情 е率
Time to leave, I'd say. Come on.
我f走了 走吧
It's so quiet.
太安o了
The bells have stopped.
R不了
Mass has begun.
撒_始了
Fuck.
死
There's something I must do.
有件事我必去做
- There's no time.  - The barge won't wait. Make a decision.
- ]rg了  - g船不等你的 你想清楚了
The Book Of Leaves or whoever tears you away. You can't have both.
~之是女人 不可兼得啊
I can. I can, if you just find a way to keep them here until I return.
我可以 我可以的 只要你能想k法船等我回
I'm not gonna be long. Just stall them, Zo.
我很快就回 想想k法 _
Please!
求你了!
There's another meaning to that card.
@就是那牌的另一意思
A journey thwarted.
被阻醯穆猛
In nominee Patris, et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
以}父 }子 }`之名
- Amen.  - Amen.
- 阿T  - 阿T
Do you fear God, Signora?
你峙律系 女士?
The wise... both fear and love God.
明的人... ι系叟c种心
Why then do you hesitate to enter His house?
那你槭颤Nq豫不敢M入他的}殿?
Because it isn't God who waits for me inside those doors.
因樵陂T後等著我的K不是上帝
tui, cum oblationibus hostiarum:
聆子民的祈\ n予他想要的}w
ut paschalibus initiata mysteriis,
如你在逾越所作的
ad aeternitatis  nobis medelam,
您的c
te operante, proficiant.
Ыo我救H
Per Dominum.
借}子耶d之w
Riders approach.
有人TR接近
Two.
善
Hell is descending upon this city.
厄\⒔蹬R在@座城市
Get yourself to safety. Now.
快 找安全地方躲起
What has happened to you?
你怎N了?
God will permit no violence.
上帝不允S暴力
You cannot disrupt a sacred Mass!
你不能打撒!
- Sheathe your weapon!  - I'm sorry, but I cannot.
- 放下武器!  - 很抱歉 我不能
Cease your intrusion. This is a House of God.
立即停止你的行 @Y是教堂
And God loves truth. Let him speak.
上帝壅嫦 他f
The Pazzis conspire against us, my family!
帕吉家族密\Ω段 我的家族!
They're in league with Rome and betray all Florence!
他c_RY盟 他背叛了佛__!
People and Liberty! Death to the Medicis!
以人民和自由的名x! 消缑赖谄婕易!
Go. Take our daughters to safety.
快走 女去安全的地方
They'll have men at the doors. Find a way out. Go!
他在大T口阎昧巳 找l路逃出去 快!
- Giuliano!  - Lorenzo!
- 朱利Z!  - 洛佐啊!
Towards the door.
朝T那跑
You betray our cause, Captain.
你背叛了我的事I L
Your cause betrays Florence.
你的事I背叛了佛__
Flee, my lady! It is a chaos of swords in there!
快跑吧 女士! @Y面刀交加啊!
Kill them!
⒐馑!
Brother! Brother! Help your family!
哥哥! 哥哥! 湍愕挠H人!
Rome is my family.
_R才是我的H人
Forgive me.
原
- Aaargh!  - Giuliano!
- 啊!  - 朱利Z!
Die, Medici scum!
死吧 美第奇渣滓!
The wife and children. Go, go!
他妻子和孩子 快 追!
Oh, Giuliano! Oh, no! No!
朱利Z! 不!
No!
不!
Come on!
快跑!
Aaargh!
啊!
Clarice... please!
克拉z... 快!
Come on.
快
I'm... I'm dying, Vanessa.
我... 我要死了 瓦妮莎
Your line will live on. In me.
我⒀永m你的血}
I'm bearing your child, your son, Giuliano.
我蚜四愕暮⒆ 你的鹤 朱利Z
Vanessa, it's too late. Vanessa, leave him.
瓦妮莎 太晚了 瓦妮莎 快走吧
Leave him! Vanessa!
e管他了! 瓦妮莎!
- No! No!  - Yes. Come on.
- 不! 不!  - 快走吧
Stay with me.
跟我
Drop it, dear cousin.
把θ拥 H鄣谋砻
No, no!
不 不!
You imagine I can't take on the lot of you?
你X得我Ω恫涣四?
Riario.
瑞阿里W
If your true loyalty is to the Medicis, Captain...
如果你真的忠\於美第奇家 L...
I suggest you take them away and leave this one to me.
我建h你他走 @留o我
- But Signora Donati...  - Has betrayed you for Rome.
- 但多{蒂夫人...  - 已背叛你投靠_R了
Leave them to each other, Signora.
他狗咬狗去吧 夫人
Children.
孩子
Hurry.
快走
No...
不...
I've prayed for this day. Today, Florence rejoices.
我一直祈\@一天的砼R 今天 佛__g欣鼓舞
Are you certain of that, Pazzi?
你真以那? 帕吉?
Aaargh!
啊!
Before you die, Lorenzo,
洛佐 R死之前
know that I'll kill every last Medici in Florence.
你知道 我⒈M佛__所有美第奇家的人
I'll wipe all evidence of your family's existence from this world!
我要⒛慵易宓暮圹E氖澜缟贤耆抹除!
Iron rusts from disuse.
Σ挥生P
Let us finish off the Medicis, scribbler,
我消缑赖谄婕易 小作家
and we might let you live.
你可以活
A Florence ruled by Pazzis? No!
帕吉家族掌管佛__? ^不!
No. I think I'd rather go down fighting.
我更意榇硕
As you wish.
遂你所
Come on. Come on!
快c 快c!
Come on! Come on!
快c! 快c!
- That won't hold long.  - The doors will hold.
- 那尾涣硕嗑玫  - T能巫
Verrocchio designed the locks.
f_基WO的i具
Giuliano? Have I lost a brother?
朱利Z呢? 我弟弟死了?
Come on! Come on, come on!
o我砸! 砸_ 砸_!
Da Vinci!
_芬奇!
Upon my arrival I saw only you.
我淼r候只看到你
- I knew you wouldn't abandon us.  - Stop. Save your strength.
- 我知道你不不管我的  - ef了 省c虐
Da Vinci!
_芬奇!
It'll be over soon, Lucrezia!
很快就有Y果啦 R克蕾RI!
I'm sorry, Leonardo. You've saved my life, and I know what it's cost y...
很抱歉 R昂{多 你救了我 我知道@δ碚f...
Ssh. Save your praise for someone who deserves it.
u 把你的美之~留o值得的人吧
I wonder which of the two men you fuck will be buried alongside you?
你希望他中的哪一槟闩阍?
You chose Florence over your own dreams.
你放粝 x窳吮Ｐl佛__
You will accept my love.
接受我的敬意
It is the least I can offer you.
我也只能向你致敬了
This ring. I know this ring.
@戒指 我JR@戒指
It's Lucrezia's.
@是R克蕾RI的
Are you fucking her... or is it more?
你跟她上床了... 或者更甚?
You better finish the job they have begun or I swear...
要N你F在退值粑 否t我l誓...
if we survive this, I'll kill you both.
如果我能生 我要把你z都⒌
God's vengeance is upon you!
I受上帝的统鹬怒吧!